<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Fitzer's House Of Code]]></title>
  <link href="http://bradbonkoski.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://bradbonkoski.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-23T17:56:26-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://bradbonkoski.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brad Bonkoski]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PHP - Conferences and Community]]></title>
    <link href="http://bradbonkoski.github.io/blog/2014/01/23/php-conferences-and-community/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-23T15:26:18-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://bradbonkoski.github.io/blog/2014/01/23/php-conferences-and-community</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today PHPTEK 2014 announced it&#8217;s conference schedule and lineup, and I have to admit I was a little disappointed.
One clear reason for this is I was not selected even though I thought the submissions I offered were really good and would have been really interesting.  (I&#8217;ll list them a little later).  So, some folks mught just label me a hater and leave, but if you would, please bear with me.</p>




<p>
I think there are two critical aspects of technology conferences.  The first is community!  This is one of the big things for PHP and why PHP has reached the level it is currently at.  The community around PHP has been relatively strong with the proponents often speaking louder and more sensibly than the antagonists.  I love going to conferences for the community, but upon looking through the speaker lineup I see very the same faces I have seen before.  And I&#8217;m assuming based on the record number of submissions there were many new people willing and excited to present, so why are we limiting the community and the particiaption in the community.  Especially when some of the talks are in fact repeats of talks given at other conferences which recordings might be out there on youtube and the like.  To summerize, PHP as a technology should not be standing still, so a talk from 4-6 months ago should not necessarily be relavent *now*, and by limiting the community we are restricting the potential growth of the community. </p>




<!-- more -->




<p>
Now to the second part of conferenes, and that is learning about new and exciting things.  This is somewhat vague, but to clarify it does not necessarily have to be specific to the language.  PHP as a language certainly is adopting, but many of the more exciting things coming up within the community is how you can us PHP with many other technologies to create robust, scalabale, enterprise systems.  I did see a lot of interesting talks in this regard, but I also saw the curious talks that were so beginner oriented that it&#8217;s like they are marketing to PHP newbies.  With that I have to give a spoiler.. there are much better and cheaper ways to learn PHP than going to the conference.  Bottom line, going to the conference is not going to teach you PHP.  So, not sure what the point is for some of the beginner classes.  I would much rather see more advanced topics around the language, tools, and interesting integrations that continue to pop up to re-enforce the maturity of the lanugae and suitability of the language in serious companies and enterprises. </p>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
